byo.com 2019-05-17

# Privacy Policy - Brew Your Own

Battenkill Communications is committed to maintaining your privacy and that of the members of your family, when it comes to use of any “personally identifiable information” you may voluntarily provide us via the internet or otherwise.

Battenkill Communications is the publisher of Brew Your Own magazine and WineMaker magazine as well as the websites www.byo.com and www.winemakermag.com. Personal information is collected by Battenkill when you decide to place an order (personally or as gifts for others), enter a contest, participate in a survey, or make a general inquiry. The information collected when you order from us or enter a contest includes some or all of the following: name, address, phone / fax number, e-mail address and credit card information. With regard to surveys in which you elect to participate, we may request demographic information (age, household income level, etc.) along with basic information regarding your reading and/or hobby interests and how Battenkill may better serve those needs. Finally, name, address and other contact information may be collected so that we can respond to any customer service issue, request for information or other general inquiry, along with information about the nature of your inquiry.

The fundamental use of the information we collect is to respond and fulfill your needs as a customer or prospective customer. In other words, the information is necessary and is used by us to send you the magazines or other products you have ordered, to process your payment, to fulfill your request to enter a contest, to acknowledge your interest in participating in a survey, or to resolve the customer service matter or other inquiry you have brought to our attention.

Demographic and other information volunteered in connection with surveys is used primarily for internal purposes to improve the company’s responsiveness to customers’ wants, needs, interests, opinions and suggestions. The aggregate findings and results of such surveys may be published. Demographic information volunteered via surveys is entered “blind” with respect to any personally identifiable information provided by individual survey respondents, and is not linked in any way with such information.

If you subscribe to one or more of our magazines, you will also receive a notice or notices about renewing your subscription prior to its expiration date. You may also receive periodic mailings from us about new products, services or upcoming events, and — from time-to-time if you signed up from offline channels — your address information may be made available to other reputable companies or organizations for marketing or information gathering purposes. Typically, such third parties serve the hobby industries in one form or another. You may request to be excluded from such mailings by contacting us directly or by taking other proactive measures, as specified below. Note we do not share information collected online.

At the time you volunteer personally identifiable information and at anytime thereafter, you can direct us not to use this information for promotional or informational mailings. At your option, you may also elect to suppress the mailing of renewal notices for any of our magazines. If you do so, your personally identifiable information will be flagged in our system as “do not promote” to correspond with your request, and you will be excluded from the related Battenkill mailings. You can also elect separately to be excluded from mailings by any third party to whom your address might otherwise be provided. You can, at any time, send such directions to the appropriate Customer Service Department at Battenkill Communications:

Brew Your Own Customer Service Department P.O. Box 469121 Escondido, CA 92046

Or contact us by e-mail: [byo@pcspublink.com](mailto:byo@pcspublink.com)

WineMaker Customer Service Department P.O. Box 469118 Escondido, CA 92046

Or contact us by e-mail: [winemaker@pcspublink.com](mailto:winemaker@pcspublink.com)

Customer Service for both magazines can also be reached by calling toll-free, 800-900-7594, 8:30am – 5:00pm Pacific Time, Monday – Friday.

There are also national clearinghouse organizations where you can register to suppress unwanted solicitations. The most prominent of these is the Direct Marketing Association (DMA). The DMA provides mail, e-mail and telephone data base “preference services” free of charge to consumers who wish to block all unsolicited direct mail, e-mail and telemarketing contacts, respectively. For more information, visit DMA’s web site at [www.the-dma.org](http://www.the-dma.org/), or contact them at (202) 955-5030.

In addition to the special measures you may take to suppress unwanted solicitations by contacting us directly, Battenkill has implemented procedures whereby files that otherwise would be used for promotional mailings are processed with the DMA to remove any records belonging to individuals who may have registered with DMA’s Mail Preference Service (but not with Battenkill).

Battenkill Communications does not directly market to children or other minors.

We maintain our corporate offices in a separate location from our customer service operations. To contact us about non-customer service related items:

Battenkill Communications 5053 Main St., Suite A Manchester Center, VT 05255

802-362-3981 802-362-2377 (fax)

Here is additional detail on the technology used on our site:

When someone visits one of our sites, we use a third-party service, Google Analytics, to collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behavior patterns. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. This information is only processed in a way which does not identify anyone. We do not make, and do not allow Google to make, any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website. We also use a Google product called Double Click for Publishers, which logs when ads are viewed, so we can tell advertisers how many impressions they received. This information is only processed in a way which does not identify anyone. We do not make, and do not allow Google to make, any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website.

As part of the registration process for our e-newsletter, we collect personal information. We use that information for a couple of reasons: to tell you about stuff you’ve asked us to tell you about; to contact you if we need to obtain or provide additional information; to check our records are right and to check every now and then that you’re happy and satisfied. We don’t rent or trade email lists with other organizations and businesses.

We use a third-party provider, MailChimp, to deliver our newsletter. We gather statistics around email opening and clicks using industry standard technologies to help us monitor and improve our e-newsletter. For more information, please see [MailChimp’s privacy notice](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/). You can unsubscribe to general mailings at any time of the day or night by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any of our emails.

When you purchase something from our store, we ask for information such as Name, Address, Phone, email, and what you bought so we can deliver your goods to you, and so we can follow up with helpful information we think you’d be interested in, like confirmation emails and how-to instructions. We do not sell information collected online to any third parties.

We use a third-party provider, OptinMonster, to track which messages on our site you like the best. Here is a copy of their [privacy policy](https://optinmonster.com/privacy/).

Credit card transactions are processed by Stripe or PayPal. We do not hold your credit card information on our servers. To check out their privacy policies, please visit here [[Stripe]](https://stripe.com/us/privacy/) [[PayPal]](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full).

You are entitled to view, amend, or delete the personal information that we hold. Email your request to [digital@byo.com](mailto:digital@byo.com)

Primarily, we use data to make sure you have the best possible experience with our brand. We take your privacy seriously.
